Samuel Varney

Phone: (608)-219-5376 | Email: samvrny@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-varney

Portfolio: samvrny.github.io/samuel-varney-portfolio | GitHub: github.com/samvrny

Open to relocation

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer leveraging skills in team environments to quickly and creatively solve problems in web development. Earned a certificate in full stack web development from the University of Wisconsin in November of 2022, with newly developed skills in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, MySQL, the MERN stack, and responsive web design. Known as a quick learner with a strong work ethic, and enjoys picking up new skills and applying them to develop and debug web applications. Have applied development skills to build several interactive applications as the sole developer, and worked with a team of six to build an interactive fullstack project that helps people choose style templates for a project. Excited to leverage skills as part of a quality-driven team to build better experiences on the web.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript ES6+, CSS, HTML, Git, MongoDB and Mongoose, MySQL and Sequelize, Express, React, Node, npm, Handlebars, Bootstrap, REST APIs

PROJECTS

Penny For Your Thoughts

Github: github.com/samvrny/theTechBlog Application: fast-island-88973.herokuapp.com

- Summary: Blog site to share thoughts and comment on others thoughts
- Role: Sole Author
- Tools: Javascript, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Express, Mysql2, Sequelize, Bcrypt, CSS

Simple Password Generator

Github: github.com/samvrny/simple-password-generator Application: samvrny.github.io/simple-password-generator

- Summary: Password generator built with Javascript
- Role: Sole Author
- Tools: Javascript, HTML, CSS

Style Buddy

GitHub: github.com/samvrny/style-buddy

Application: protected-chamber-44327.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Website built for picking and saving different styles like colors and fonts to use in a project
- Role: Project lead, front-end Javascript developer and back-end consultant

 Tools: Javascript, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap, Apollo/GraphQL, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Bcrypt, Concurrently, React

EXPERIENCE

Delivery Driver 2020 - Present Doordash INC. Boulder CO and Woodbury, MN

Worked with vendors and consumers to ensure the correct orders were delivered in a timely manner. Constant critical thinking needed to plan routes, ensure correct orders, and locate customers and deliver their orders.

Key Accomplishments:

- Managed time as a freelance contractor to deliver orders on time 97.34% of the time, delivering over 2161 orders
- Maintained a 5 star (out of 5) customer rating through my work experience

Laborer 2020-2021

Small Family Farm CSA

LaFarge, WI

Phone: (608)-625-4178

Supervisor: Adam Varney

Worked with teams and crews in a high-paced, high-energy environment to take vegetables from the beginning of their life cycle in the spring all the way to their delivery to the consumer. Key Accomplishments:

- Completed challenging tasks operating heavy machinery
- Worked with large teams to coordinate and accomplish tasks in a timely and efficient manner
- Trained new employees

Server 2018-2020

The Old Fashioned Madison, WI

Phone: (608)-310-4545 Supervisor: Brandon Mueller Served customers from all walks of life in a high-traffic and high-paced supper club

Key Accomplishments:

- Satisfied up to 100 guests per day
- Coordinated delivery of food and beverage, referring to complicated tickets to ensure the correct order made it to each guest
- Trained new servers and food-runners
- Accomplished mandatory lists of cleaning services after each shift

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

University of Wisconsin Madison, WI